<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of Kevin</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000"/>
 <updated>2018-01-16T20:19:16-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kevin</name>
   <email>kguebert93@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Sharing Ideas</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/16/sharing-ideas.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/16/sharing-ideas</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing I love being a part of is getting an idea and seeing how far you can take it. Over the past couple years, I’ve been fortunate enough to participate in a couple of these ideas that broke the barrier between idea and product. My favorite one was Activity Buzz - a service that helped parents find the best activities for their kids. Unfortunately, it didn’t quite pan out. But, in the semi-failure, many lessons were learned so I’d count it as a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas though are just ideas unless you act on them. They sit in your brain or on a piece of paper or in a spreadsheet for eternity unless some action is taken. The number of times I’ve spent a hours going down a hole and then not act on that idea is…countless. In college I even semi-designed something that never came to fruition. This past year, a friend and myself even submitted our idea to a bootcamp. Most ideas though, well they go in the long list of “that would be cool.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I’m sharing one of those ideas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;draw-with-your-voice&quot;&gt;Draw With Your Voice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back maybe last year or the year before that, Reddit had an application where users could color in pixels on a white canvas on the internet. It would all depend on how many users were drawing, consistency, frequency, and many other factors. Often times, if you wanted to draw something, someone else would come in and override what you just drew with their own drawing. Pixel by pixel, different images emerged in different spots on this canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought: what if you could do that with your voice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with Alexa, I wondered how cool it would be if everyone who had an Alexa was able to “draw” on a shared canvas on the internet but with the restriction of only being able to saw what you want. Commands like “draw a line from the top left to the bottom right” or “draw a circle in the middle” were some example commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be difficult though - getting commands from voice data points to X,Y positions on a canvas would be…tricky to say the least. But, in a skewed way of thinking (and with some technical prowess), you could imagine that people could then “paint” or “create art” with their voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any thoughts about this? Let me know &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kevinguebert&quot;&gt;@kevinguebert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Listen to this podcast - Tim Ferriss interviews Terry Crews</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/terry-crews-podcast.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/14/terry-crews-podcast</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve found my favorite podcast of this year. Granted we are only 14 days into it, but if I were to recommend any podcast right now to anyone, I would highly recommend Tim Ferriss’ interview of Terry Crews title &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2017/12/20/terry-crews-how-to-have-do-and-be-all-you-want/&quot;&gt;Terry Crews — How to Have, Do, and Be All You Want&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, I didn’t know too much about Terry Crews going into the podcast, but, he the way he talks and shares is spell-bounding. I won’t share too much of the details, but one part of the interview Terry Crews talks about how if you want to have something or be something, then &lt;strong&gt;be&lt;/strong&gt; it. His example is this - if you want to be rich, then right now, you are rich. Be rich. So the question you ask yourself is, &lt;strong&gt;what would a rich person do?&lt;/strong&gt;. Or if you want to be a writer - be a writer. What would a writer do? Well a writer would start writing every day, start taking notes, and publish a book. You are a writer. You are rich. So be it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Finding Your Peak Time - My Morning Routine</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/12/morning-routine.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/12/morning-routine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you Goole or search on Medium for “morning routine”, you are bound to get thousands of pages of people describing their morning routine and why it is the best one out there. From article titles like “What the 5 Most Successful People Do Every Morning” to “Do these 10 Things Every Morning for Maximum Productivity”, there are slew of habits, actions, and routines that people are willing to talk about and prescribe you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, over the past 2 years of working on how I spend my morning, I have decided on one main point: &lt;em&gt;you pick the best way to start your day that fits you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I’ve come to that is from interacting with people and talking with them - everyone is different. Case in point: night owls will not benefit from waking up before dawn and getting started. Night owls work best in the silence of the night when everyone else is asleep. Some people get up and read to invigorate the brain, others meditate to calm the brain, some people journal, others hit the gym. What I’m trying to say is to experiment to find out what works best with you - take a hard look at when your maximum productivity is, when you feel the best, and then capture that energy by creating routines that build that fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what works best for me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve come to realize and understand that I am more of a morning person. 100% I love waking up before others in the quiet of the morning, having my coffee, and starting the day with decisions I make instead of other’s. That means I am usually in bed pretty early but that is a different post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what a typical morning looks like for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:30AM Wakeup alarm by Jocko Willink (See &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/01/07/using-sleep-full-potential.html&quot;&gt;Sleep &amp;amp; Discipline to learn more&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downstairs to start my kettle for coffee &amp;amp; I make sure to have about half of my Nalgene of water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aeropress Coffee (if you are looking for a good, quick, coffee system, I highly recommend Aeropress. Learning about it and the science behind it was enlightening)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get out my regular looking journal - it is one of those notebooks you see in school, spiral bound, where if you mess up the spirals then the thing is a pain - mine right now is blue and wide ruled. Sometimes I have college ruled, but I like wide as it seems to be the right amount of time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With my coffee and journal, I usually spend on average 25-30 minutes journaling. This equates to one page (front and back) in my journal. Journal topics have a wide range, but the main focus is to get thoughts out of my head and on to paper so they don’t bother me any longer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next is a choice: I either write a post like this to share what I have learned &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; I read for another 45 minutes and take notes so I learn more thus share more posts like this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Around 6:45/7:00 is the first time I check my phone. I try and go as long as possible without checking it - around this time is usually when I start making breakfast and thus would like some music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:00-7:40, breakfast, preparing for work, making my lunch - the usual morning activities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:40 - on my bike, headed to work - I am fortunate enough to be able to bike every morning - it gets my heart rate up a little, that fresh morning air, and it’s pretty quiet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:00 - at my desk, starting the work day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one point in there that I would like to highlight and share more - &lt;strong&gt;don’t check your phone.&lt;/strong&gt; This one I have come to enjoy the most. Why? Well because when you check your phone, you are then subject to the asks of others. Others could be text messages or phone calls, but it could also be Tweets, Likes, News Updates, and more. This immediately changes the focus from yourself to the call and ask of others. Most people, myself included, have their minds crowded and jumbled up then - it is hard to journal when you have the other apps and notifications in your mind. This also has the dual side effect of getting you out of your bed - if instead you just roll over and check your phone - you can get lost in the scroll for way to much time. Get out of bed and get after it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try the no-phone rule out. Maybe it’s the first 30 minutes of your morning just drinking coffee in silence. Or maybe it’s just 10 minutes every morning. I believe it will help start your day by allowing you to make decisions about how you want your day to go instead of being a slave to the call of others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Explore/Exploit Algorithm in Decisions & Regret</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/10/explore-exploit.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/10/explore-exploit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post inspired from: &lt;strong&gt;Algorithms to Live By&lt;/strong&gt; by Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore/Exploit:&lt;/strong&gt; In the explore phase, we &lt;em&gt;gather&lt;/em&gt; all the information, and the exploit phase is &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; that information you have to make the best decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decisions&quot;&gt;Decisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we look at the Explore/Exploit algorithm, we can see that an old phrase is actually has some truth behind it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The grass is always greener on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have all heard that saying before, but, did you know that there is some mathematically proof that supports it? If you do not have much data, then the unknown has a higher chance of success, even if we expect it to be no different, or “if it’s just as likely to be worse” (41). Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths state it as the “untested rookie is worth more than the veteran of seemingly equal ability, precisely because we know less about him.” Therein lies the kicker though - once we have enough data, then we make a decision based with the provided data that could possibly change the scenario around. So next draft you see - whether it is football, baseball, basketball, or any sport - remember that the rookies getting the huge contracts are getting the huge contracts because of the chance that they are the best (a higher chance of success).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regret&quot;&gt;Regret&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To try and fail is at least to learn; to fail to try is to suffer the inestimable loss of what might have been” - Chester Barnard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at Explore/Exploit is to frame it in the light of trying to live “&lt;strong&gt;a life with minimal regret&lt;/strong&gt;” (43). The authors share a story about how Jeff Bezos, founder of Amazon.com, took the risk of moving from his well paying job to the online bookstore. They quote him as saying it was an easy decision. Why? Well Bezos used the idea of living a life with minimal regret and did an exercise with it: he imagined himself at 80 years old and then thought back on his life and knew he wanted to have minimal regrets. In this exercise, he knew that not taking the risk would lead to regret, thus, he took the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have then spent years looking to find a way to guarantee minimal regret - the most famous algorithm is called the &lt;strong&gt;Upper Confidence Bound.&lt;/strong&gt; This algorithm makes a decision not based on what has performed best in the past, but what &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; perform the best in the future. To explain it, the authors share that “if you have never been to a restaurant before, then for all you know it could be great. Even if you have gone there once or twice, and tried a couple of dishes, you might not have enough information to rule out the possibility that it could yet prove better” (44).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Upper Confidence Bound algorithm has a sense of optimism about it - the optimism that what you are trying could be the best. “By focusing on the best that an option could be, these algorithms give a boost to possibilities we know less about” (45). What does that mean for you and me? If we think about the world in the terms of these algorithms, then “you should be excited to meet new people and try new things - to assume the best about them, in the absence of evidence to the contrary” (45) because the chances of finding the best that way are better than not even trying at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Look-Then-Leap Rule - Explained</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/09/look-then-leap.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/09/look-then-leap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post inspired from: &lt;strong&gt;Algorithms to Live By&lt;/strong&gt; by Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loop-Then-Leap Rule:&lt;/strong&gt; “You set a predetermined amount of time for ‘looking’ - that is, exploring your options, gathering data - in which you categorically don’t choose anyone, no matter how impressive. After that point, you enter the ‘leap’ phase, prepared to instantly commit to anyone who outshines the best applicant you saw in the look phase.” (13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenario: You are interviewing for a new secretary and want to pick the best applicant. Once you have passed on a candidate, you cannot go back and pick them. You are interviewing at random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-applicants&quot;&gt;1 Applicants&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hire them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-applicants&quot;&gt;2 Applicants&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2 applicants, you have a 50/50 shot at hiring the best one. Either pick the first one, or, if you don’t, you have to pick the second one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-applicants&quot;&gt;3 Applicants&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have 3 applicants, ranked as the best being 1, second best being 2, and worst being 3. With 3 applicants, there are 6 possible scenarios in which you can interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1-2-3 (that is: best, second best, worst)&lt;br /&gt;
1-3-2&lt;br /&gt;
2-1-3&lt;br /&gt;
2-3-1&lt;br /&gt;
3-1-2&lt;br /&gt;
3-2-1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 3 applicants, &lt;em&gt;we can actually do just as well as we did with just 2 applicants - a 50/50 shot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we see the first applicant, we don’t have any baseline information so we pass up on them to gather more data (the “look”) phase. When we see the final applicant, we only have one person so we have to pick them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the second option, there is more room. With the “Look-Then-Leap” Rule - &lt;strong&gt;if the second option is better than the first one, then you leap. If it is not, then you move to the next one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s visualize this - remember, you are on the second candidate because the first candidate was your “look” - or information gathering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 -&lt;u&gt; 2 &lt;/u&gt;- 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, we have already passed up on the best candidate (1), so this would be a Failure.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 -&lt;u&gt; 3 &lt;/u&gt;- 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the one above, we have already passed up on the best candidate (1), so also a Failure.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 -&lt;u&gt; 1 &lt;/u&gt;- 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, the second candidate is better than the first one (1 is better than 2), so you would leap on this candidate - Success!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 -&lt;u&gt; 3 &lt;/u&gt;- 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second candidate is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; better than the first one (3 is worse than 2), so you would then move on to the 3rd candidate. The 3rd candidate is better than the first one, so you would then leap - Success!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 -&lt;u&gt; 1 &lt;/u&gt;- 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, the second candidate is better than the first one (1 is better than 3), so you would leap on this candidate - Success!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 -&lt;u&gt; 2 &lt;/u&gt;- 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this last scenario, the second candidate is better than the first candidate (2 is better than 3), so that means we would leap by the rules. Unfortunately that means we miss out on the last candidate, the 1 - Failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the data above we have 3 successes and 3 failures - thus a 50/50 chance when we have 3 candidates - tada!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successes: [2,1,3], [2,3,1], [3,1,2]&lt;br /&gt;
Failures: [1,2,3], [1,3,2], [3,2,1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue on an enumerate more candidates - 4, 5, 6, etc. - the place where you end up drawing the line between looking and leaping is actually 37% (the 37% Rule).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;37-rule&quot;&gt;37% Rule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing the best candidate, you only have a 37% chance of hiring the best possible applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it works:&lt;/strong&gt; You look at the first 37% of the applicants, not choosing any of them, then after that, leap for anyone that is better than all those you have seen so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time you are making a decision over a large amount of data and you are trying to decide the “best”, it may be worth it to consider this algorithm!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Who's Fault Is It?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/08/whos-fault-is-it.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/08/whos-fault-is-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love my routine. I love having a plan, knowing what the future holds, and knowing what the expectations are for me. I may be addicted to it. The feeling of moving forward, of progress, towards making something (usually myself) better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why, however, that interruptions to my routine can cause rifts in my mood. These interruptions often come in the form of other people - friends, family, coworkers, etc. - that have a different agenda or a different plan or idea. Instead of only focusing on myself, now I have to take into consideration other people’s wants and needs. This often times breaks my routine. Instead of going grocery shopping on a Sunday and planning my week out, I’m watching NFL football at a brewery eating out. Instead of getting some exercise or meal prepping, I’m hanging out on a couch with other people not doing that. I have come to loathe the unplanned/sitting around a couch doing nothing with no plan/browsing the phone moments. I would rather be by myself moving in some direction (hopefully making forward progress) instead of sitting around with my friends with no plan. And when I am in those “less desirable” situations, I get frustrated, moody, anxious, and angry. I get short with my phrases and retreat into silence. I start blaming others for interrupting my time and my precious routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, it isn’t their fault. It isn’t my friend’s fault, my family’s, or my coworker’s. They have no control over my routine, they have no control over my reactions. More often than not, they don’t even know what my routine and goals are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my fault. The salty mood, that anxious feeling, that frustration I’m building up - it’s all because of me. I am responsible for not making my routine happen. No one else. Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I need to meet my macros today and hit my calorie goal? I have to plan for that. I can’t just assume food and nutrient-dense foods will fall out of the sky. I am responsible for what I eat and when I eat. We are going for a hike and in the morning I usually have a protein-rich snack before lunch? Well I need to plan to have that on the hike or an alternate later. I go to a restaurant and order something that isn’t in MyFitnessPal? I need to take note of the ingredients and log them in manually. I know I won’t have time on Sunday to go to the grocery store? I need to go on Thursday night and plan ahead for the upcoming week instead of waiting for late Sunday night or later in the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These problems are my responsibility. Other people do not have control or know what I want to do unless I voice them or make them a priority. My ego is clouding my judgment and controlling my mood when in reality, ego is the problem. My routine and goals are not hard - they don’t require me to dedicate hours every day to meet some goal. They are small, incremental, that allow me to grow and progress every day. I am responsible for making sure that I progress every day, no one else. Me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sleep & Discipline</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/07/using-sleep-full-potential.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/07/using-sleep-full-potential</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post inspired from: &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; by Jocko Willink&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep can be elusive. It can be frustrating. It can be restless. It can be tiring. But sleep can also be fruitful and it can re-energize. Everyone needs to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be frank with you: I am usually in bed by 9:00PM and asleep before 10:00PM every night. I try and read something before I go to bed to help calm the mind, so sometimes it is closer to 10:00PM, other times I’m asleep right at 9. I love it. While I am very fortunate to be able to sleep in a comfy bed every night, sometimes I struggle with sleep - falling asleep, staying asleep, and, maybe most importantly, getting out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many factors seem to effect the quality of sleep - Jocko Willink in &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; offers the argument that “if you are in good physical condition, eating clean, and have a clear mind” (103) then sleep comes faster, easier, and requires less of it. Right there is &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; benefit of working out, eating well, and calming one’s mind (through reading, journaling, meditation, etc). One quote that really stands out to me from this section is that Jocko “choose(s) not to sleep in. I don’t give in to the temptation of the warm blankets and soft pillow. I mobilize the will to get me out of bed and into the game.” (109) &lt;em&gt;Mobilize the will.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The follow pages are then a good introduction into how Jocko the Navy Seal operates - he is up at 4:30AM and every morning posts a picture of his watch showing 4:34AM on Twitter. Why so early? Well if you wake up at 4:30, work out like he says, and start the day, then you will most likely be very, very tired by 9:30PM to fall asleep easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“… a vast majority of the world is still sleep. You aren’t. You are up getting after it. The world is yours when you are up before the enemy” (104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you think? 4:30AM every morning, &lt;strong&gt;even weekends&lt;/strong&gt;. Do you think you can do it? Get after it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/@jockowillink&quot;&gt;Jocko on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see his 4:34AM tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro-tip from Joe: Jocko has an album out call &lt;strong&gt;Psychological Warfare&lt;/strong&gt; on Google Play and iTunes where the first track is called “Wake up and Get After it”. Set that bad boy as your alarm and it will be tough staying in bed with Jocko’s voice right next to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stoicism & Discipline Equals Freedom</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/04/the-best-for-yourself.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/04/the-best-for-yourself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am one day in and 39 pages deep into &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt;, and I would already highly recommend it to anyone. This morning I came across a couple passages that I wanted to share that I believe relate very much to Stoicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How long are you going to wait before you demand the best for yourself? - Epictetus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above question is short and simple, but initiates a deeper question and conversation I can have with myself. Jocko Willink, author of &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; goes even deeper into these types of questions. He states that “knowledge is the ultimate weapon” (28) and the path to gaining knowledge is to “Question &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t accept anything as truth.” The rest of the page talks then about external questions that we may face every day - words we don’t know, concepts we may not understand, etc. But, the more important questions are the ones like the quote above. Jocko shares it as “Question yourself every day.” All the time, question my actions, my thoughts, my progress, my learning. Question everything about me. And they are very simple questions, but like above, very powerful. Below is my favorite excerpt from this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; what I want to be? &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt;? Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; all I’ve got – is this everything I can give? Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; going to be &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; life? Do I &lt;em&gt;accept&lt;/em&gt; that? - Jocko Willink (29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What bombshells of questions. Why? Well because we all know that we can do better. I could feel it in myself while reading those questions that I am not giving it all I’ve got. I know I can do better and Jocko challenges us to fight back and not accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten pages later, Jocko provides us hope with these questions. I am not going to lie, after reading &lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;, I actually felt a bit discouraged. Elon Musk seems to be so far and above everyone else that some people even revere him in a god-like way. Reading about all his accomplishments, his challenges, and his successes, I couldn’t help but reflect on myself a little and compare some of what I’ve done to him. Foolish, I know, but still in the back of my mind, and also a very negative exercise. In his chapter on “Nature vs. Nurture,” Jocko simplifies it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is not about nature or nuture: It is about choice. The people who are successful &lt;em&gt;decide&lt;/em&gt; they are going to be successful. They make that choice. - Jocko Willink (39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he provides more hope - “It is never too late to make that choice…Choose to make yourself smarter and stronger and healthier…Don’t let nature or nuture make you. Choose to Make. Your. Self.” (39) Next time then when I start comparing myself to others, start looking at successful people, I have to remind myself that it is a choice. A choice that I can also make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.app.goo.gl/tztrT92NxOAY3PiL2&quot;&gt;Download Epictetus Wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Behat and JS? Go CasperJS</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/behat-and-casper.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/behat-and-casper</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today while writing tests (shocking, I know), I came across an interesting and unknown (at the time) scenario. For the site, I wanted to test and make sure a certain element was showing up on the page. At the time, I was writing Behat tests to do some functionality and the tests are very simple to write, so I decided to try and create a simple test for my element. &lt;em&gt;Usually&lt;/em&gt; this is pretty straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Given I am on &quot;/&quot; #the homepage
Then I should see &quot;.ad-block&quot; element
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, I am checking to make sure an ad is showing up on the page. &lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt; the problem is that the ads do not populate on first page load. They have to send a request to get the ads and populate them. So, this means for Behat, it is &lt;strong&gt;not waiting&lt;/strong&gt; for those ads to load! The driver I am using is the Goutte driver, so any chance at creating a FeatureContext is not possible with javascript. Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Given I am on &quot;/&quot;
And I wait 4 seconds
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I learned today! Luckily, Behat is our &lt;strong&gt;Behavior Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt; testing framework, but we also use CasperJS for our testing. In fact, there were already tests written for other ads on the site. The more you know!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Elon Musk in the Wizard of Oz</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/02/elon-musk.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/02/elon-musk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Elon-Musk-SpaceX-Fantastic-Future/dp/0062301233&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ashlee Vance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in college studying for my degree, I took a couple classes on design, prototyping, and building interfaces. One topic or phrase that often came up in the early lessons on prototyping and design was the idea of “Wizard of Oz.grb” In short terms, this means that you prototype an app or design without actually making it fully work. This could be as simple as a powerpoint presentation where you “tapped” on certain areas of the slide that made it “look” like you were interacting with an app, but in reality, you were just advancing to the next slide. Or it could be a bit more intense - instead of creating a full-fledged mobile application, it could be easier to prototype in HTML and CSS to make it &lt;strong&gt;look&lt;/strong&gt; like you had a fully functioning app. Prototypes in this stage are often used to attract customers, gain feedback, and look for improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;, I learned that Elon Musk and Tesla also used similar practices for the Model S sedan. Ashlee Vance states that at a press event in March of 2009, the car that was shown (from a difference), was “Wizard of Oz”-ed  to “remind people that Teslas had a credible plan to make electric cars more mainstream…” Bruce Leak, a Tesla owner at the event said in regards to the body panels and the hood that “they could just slide…right off” This car is a perfect example of prototyping and showcasing an early version of a product even though “the sedan barely held together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building the next app then, maybe it is better to have early prototypes that don’t function fully to gain the valuable feedback or gain some momentum before the launch. Who knows, maybe it will take years to make it to market like the Model S did, but with that much feedback and refinement, it could also be a success like the Model S.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
