<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of Kevin</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000"/>
 <updated>2018-01-08T19:27:35-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kevin</name>
   <email>kguebert93@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Who's Fault Is It?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/08/whos-fault-is-it.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/08/whos-fault-is-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love my routine. I love having a plan, knowing what the future holds, and knowing what the expectations are for me. I may be addicted to it. The feeling of moving forward, of progress, towards making something (usually myself) better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why, however, that interruptions to my routine can cause rifts in my mood. These interruptions often come in the form of other people - friends, family, coworkers, etc. - that have a different agenda or a different plan or idea. Instead of only focusing on myself, now I have to take into consideration other people’s wants and needs. This often times breaks my routine. Instead of going grocery shopping on a Sunday and planning my week out, I’m watching NFL football at a brewery eating out. Instead of getting some exercise or meal prepping, I’m hanging out on a couch with other people not doing that. I have come to loathe the unplanned/sitting around a couch doing nothing with no plan/browsing the phone moments. I would rather be by myself moving in some direction (hopefully making forward progress) instead of sitting around with my friends with no plan. And when I am in those “less desirable” situations, I get frustrated, moody, anxious, and angry. I get short with my phrases and retreat into silence. I start blaming others for interrupting my time and my precious routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, it isn’t their fault. It isn’t my friend’s fault, my family’s, or my coworker’s. They have no control over my routine, they have no control over my reactions. More often than not, they don’t even know what my routine and goals are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my fault. The salty mood, that anxious feeling, that frustration I’m building up - it’s all because of me. I am responsible for not making my routine happen. No one else. Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I need to meet my macros today and hit my calorie goal? I have to plan for that. I can’t just assume food and nutrient-dense foods will fall out of the sky. I am responsible for what I eat and when I eat. We are going for a hike and in the morning I usually have a protein-rich snack before lunch? Well I need to plan to have that on the hike or an alternate later. I go to a restaurant and order something that isn’t in MyFitnessPal? I need to take note of the ingredients and log them in manually. I know I won’t have time on Sunday to go to the grocery store? I need to go on Thursday night and plan ahead for the upcoming week instead of waiting for late Sunday night or later in the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These problems are my responsibility. Other people do not have control or know what I want to do unless I voice them or make them a priority. My ego is clouding my judgment and controlling my mood when in reality, ego is the problem. My routine and goals are not hard - they don’t require me to dedicate hours every day to meet some goal. They are small, incremental, that allow me to grow and progress every day. I am responsible for making sure that I progress every day, no one else. Me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sleep & Discipline</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/07/using-sleep-full-potential.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/07/using-sleep-full-potential</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post inspired from: &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; by Jocko Willink&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep can be elusive. It can be frustrating. It can be restless. It can be tiring. But sleep can also be fruitful and it can re-energize. Everyone needs to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be frank with you: I am usually in bed by 9:00PM and asleep before 10:00PM every night. I try and read something before I go to bed to help calm the mind, so sometimes it is closer to 10:00PM, other times I’m asleep right at 9. I love it. While I am very fortunate to be able to sleep in a comfy bed every night, sometimes I struggle with sleep - falling asleep, staying asleep, and, maybe most importantly, getting out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many factors seem to effect the quality of sleep - Jocko Willink in &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; offers the argument that “if you are in good physical condition, eating clean, and have a clear mind” (103) then sleep comes faster, easier, and requires less of it. Right there is &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; benefit of working out, eating well, and calming one’s mind (through reading, journaling, meditation, etc). One quote that really stands out to me from this section is that Jocko “choose(s) not to sleep in. I don’t give in to the temptation of the warm blankets and soft pillow. I mobilize the will to get me out of bed and into the game.” (109) &lt;em&gt;Mobilize the will.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The follow pages are then a good introduction into how Jocko the Navy Seal operates - he is up at 4:30AM and every morning posts a picture of his watch showing 4:34AM on Twitter. Why so early? Well if you wake up at 4:30, work out like he says, and start the day, then you will most likely be very, very tired by 9:30PM to fall asleep easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“… a vast majority of the world is still sleep. You aren’t. You are up getting after it. The world is yours when you are up before the enemy” (104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you think? 4:30AM every morning, &lt;strong&gt;even weekends&lt;/strong&gt;. Do you think you can do it? Get after it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/@jockowillink&quot;&gt;Jocko on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see his 4:34AM tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro-tip from Joe: Jocko has an album out call &lt;strong&gt;Psychological Warfare&lt;/strong&gt; on Google Play and iTunes where the first track is called “Wake up and Get After it”. Set that bad boy as your alarm and it will be tough staying in bed with Jocko’s voice right next to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stoicism & Discipline Equals Freedom</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/04/the-best-for-yourself.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/04/the-best-for-yourself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am one day in and 39 pages deep into &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt;, and I would already highly recommend it to anyone. This morning I came across a couple passages that I wanted to share that I believe relate very much to Stoicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How long are you going to wait before you demand the best for yourself? - Epictetus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above question is short and simple, but initiates a deeper question and conversation I can have with myself. Jocko Willink, author of &lt;strong&gt;Discipline Equals Freedom Field Manual&lt;/strong&gt; goes even deeper into these types of questions. He states that “knowledge is the ultimate weapon” (28) and the path to gaining knowledge is to “Question &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t accept anything as truth.” The rest of the page talks then about external questions that we may face every day - words we don’t know, concepts we may not understand, etc. But, the more important questions are the ones like the quote above. Jocko shares it as “Question yourself every day.” All the time, question my actions, my thoughts, my progress, my learning. Question everything about me. And they are very simple questions, but like above, very powerful. Below is my favorite excerpt from this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; what I want to be? &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt;? Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; all I’ve got – is this everything I can give? Is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; going to be &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; life? Do I &lt;em&gt;accept&lt;/em&gt; that? - Jocko Willink (29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What bombshells of questions. Why? Well because we all know that we can do better. I could feel it in myself while reading those questions that I am not giving it all I’ve got. I know I can do better and Jocko challenges us to fight back and not accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten pages later, Jocko provides us hope with these questions. I am not going to lie, after reading &lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;, I actually felt a bit discouraged. Elon Musk seems to be so far and above everyone else that some people even revere him in a god-like way. Reading about all his accomplishments, his challenges, and his successes, I couldn’t help but reflect on myself a little and compare some of what I’ve done to him. Foolish, I know, but still in the back of my mind, and also a very negative exercise. In his chapter on “Nature vs. Nurture,” Jocko simplifies it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is not about nature or nuture: It is about choice. The people who are successful &lt;em&gt;decide&lt;/em&gt; they are going to be successful. They make that choice. - Jocko Willink (39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he provides more hope - “It is never too late to make that choice…Choose to make yourself smarter and stronger and healthier…Don’t let nature or nuture make you. Choose to Make. Your. Self.” (39) Next time then when I start comparing myself to others, start looking at successful people, I have to remind myself that it is a choice. A choice that I can also make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.app.goo.gl/tztrT92NxOAY3PiL2&quot;&gt;Download Epictetus Wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Behat and JS? Go CasperJS</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/behat-and-casper.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/behat-and-casper</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today while writing tests (shocking, I know), I came across an interesting and unknown (at the time) scenario. For the site, I wanted to test and make sure a certain element was showing up on the page. At the time, I was writing Behat tests to do some functionality and the tests are very simple to write, so I decided to try and create a simple test for my element. &lt;em&gt;Usually&lt;/em&gt; this is pretty straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Given I am on &quot;/&quot; #the homepage
Then I should see &quot;.ad-block&quot; element
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, I am checking to make sure an ad is showing up on the page. &lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt; the problem is that the ads do not populate on first page load. They have to send a request to get the ads and populate them. So, this means for Behat, it is &lt;strong&gt;not waiting&lt;/strong&gt; for those ads to load! The driver I am using is the Goutte driver, so any chance at creating a FeatureContext is not possible with javascript. Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Given I am on &quot;/&quot;
And I wait 4 seconds
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I learned today! Luckily, Behat is our &lt;strong&gt;Behavior Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt; testing framework, but we also use CasperJS for our testing. In fact, there were already tests written for other ads on the site. The more you know!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Elon Musk in the Wizard of Oz</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/02/elon-musk.html"/>
   <updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/02/elon-musk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Elon-Musk-SpaceX-Fantastic-Future/dp/0062301233&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ashlee Vance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in college studying for my degree, I took a couple classes on design, prototyping, and building interfaces. One topic or phrase that often came up in the early lessons on prototyping and design was the idea of “Wizard of Oz.grb” In short terms, this means that you prototype an app or design without actually making it fully work. This could be as simple as a powerpoint presentation where you “tapped” on certain areas of the slide that made it “look” like you were interacting with an app, but in reality, you were just advancing to the next slide. Or it could be a bit more intense - instead of creating a full-fledged mobile application, it could be easier to prototype in HTML and CSS to make it &lt;strong&gt;look&lt;/strong&gt; like you had a fully functioning app. Prototypes in this stage are often used to attract customers, gain feedback, and look for improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/strong&gt;, I learned that Elon Musk and Tesla also used similar practices for the Model S sedan. Ashlee Vance states that at a press event in March of 2009, the car that was shown (from a difference), was “Wizard of Oz”-ed  to “remind people that Teslas had a credible plan to make electric cars more mainstream…” Bruce Leak, a Tesla owner at the event said in regards to the body panels and the hood that “they could just slide…right off” This car is a perfect example of prototyping and showcasing an early version of a product even though “the sedan barely held together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building the next app then, maybe it is better to have early prototypes that don’t function fully to gain the valuable feedback or gain some momentum before the launch. Who knows, maybe it will take years to make it to market like the Model S did, but with that much feedback and refinement, it could also be a success like the Model S.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
