<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Guebert</title>
    <description>Write a description of your website here.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:48:58 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:48:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Better Than You Were Yesterday</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You are discovering who you are, and what you want, and what you are willing to do. You are finding that the solutions to your particular problems have to be tailored to you, personally and precisely. You are less concerned with the actions of other people, because you have plenty to do yourself.” (110)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3: Compare yourself to who you were yesterday, not to who someone else is today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing to others consumes us. It is one thing that many of us do daily - a job, a car, a physique, money, friends, etc. Comparing ourselves to the versions of others is also detrimental and unfair. How can we take &lt;em&gt;one area&lt;/em&gt; of our life and compare it to the life of someone else? That guy driving the fancy new car seems to have it all, but he could be lonely and wanting a family that you have. The woman running every day may be able to run faster and farther than you, but is struggling financially. Everyone has their own problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Rule 3, Dr. Peterson talks about paying attention - being more aware and opening up our eyes to the possibilities of growth. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJG698U2Mvo&quot;&gt;Watch this video and try it out for yourself&lt;/a&gt;. We all do it - we have a focused view of the possibilities. “I want that higher up position because my life will get better.” That isn’t a bad goal, but a bad reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson’s solution is very simple though - &lt;strong&gt;“What could I do, that I would do, to make Life a little better?”&lt;/strong&gt;(109) Think about that. What is one thing you could do today to make life a little better? It could be organizing your bills. It could be going for a walk. It could be messaging the people you’ve been putting off. The beauty of it is that if you ask yourself that question every day and follow through, then in a short amount of time you life will have improved dramatically. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=the+1%25+daily+rule&amp;amp;oq=the+1%25+daily+rule&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i64l3.6532j0j3&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Others have wrote&lt;/a&gt; similar articles about it calling it the 1% rule (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1percentrulebook.com/launch&quot;&gt;someone even has a book about it&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help completing that task? You can tie a reward with it. “If I pay all my bills, I’ll grab a cup of coffee.” Simple, yet effective (as long as you make sure to follow through on the coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What could I do, that I would do, to make Life a little better?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/26/compare-yourself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/26/compare-yourself</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who Are Your Friends</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you surround yourself with people who support your upward aim, they will not tolerate your cynicism and destructiveness. They will instead encourage you when you do good for yourself and others and punish you carefully when you do not.” (82)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3: Make Friends with People Who Want the Best for You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the first three rules, if I were to recommend a must-read chapter I would recommend Rule 3. Dr. Peterson touches on friends, friendship, and poses the question of why some people chose friends who aren’t good for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you have a friend whose friendship you wouldn’t recommend to your sister, or your father, or your son, why would you have such a friend for yourself?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of recommending a friend is a deep, thought filled question. Personally, it struck a chord. If I wouldn’t recommend this person to hang out with someone else, why am I hanging out with them? You may think loyalty is the answer, right? Dr. Peterson tears that logic apart though - “Friendship is a reciproal arrangement. You are not morally obliged to support someone who is. making the world a worse place.” “You should choose people who want things to be better, not worse” (82).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you are thinking to yourself “but I’m a good person, this person needs my help.” Take a step back and actively look at that relationship. Maybe you are a good person who wants to do the right thing for your friend. But make sure it isn’t an alternative reason. Are you sure you aren’t trying to draw attention to yourself by highlighting your “compassion and good-will”? Or are you sure you’re not trying to help someone to make you feel better about your place and character? Or are you trying to help someone “because it’s easier to look virtuous when standing alongside someone utterly irresponsible”? (79)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may look like you are making progress - long talks with your friend about the possibilities and how you both are doing everything possible. But that isn’t real progress. Instead you may be &lt;em&gt;enabling the delusion&lt;/em&gt; which can end up being worse than you not being there at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does Dr. Peterson recommend? There are tips scattered throughout the chapter of questions to ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Are you so sure th person crying out to be saved has not decided a thousand times to accept his lot of pointless and worsening suffering, &lt;em&gt;simply because it is easier than shouldering any true responsibility&lt;/em&gt;?” (79)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Before you help someone, you should find out why that person is in trouble. You shouldn’t merely assume that he or she is a noble victim of unjust circumstances and explotation…if you buy the story that everything terrible just happened on its own, with no personal responsibility on the part of the victim, you deny that person all agency in the past.” (80)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 3 makes you think about your life and your friendships. Examine them and ask yourself if you would recommend that person as a friend to others. If you wouldn’t, find out why. Dr. Peterson states “it’s a good thing, not a selfish thing, to choose people who are good for you” (82). Lastly though, Dr. Peterson also states the opposite - it is selfish to use some of these justifications for leaving someone truly in need. Take some time and reflect today on those relationships in your life: maybe you think you may be “saving” someone when in fact you could be doing more harm than good, maybe there are relationships where it is not reciprocal, maybe it is time to reevaluate your position. At the end of the day, look to the rule - “make friends with people who want the best for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/24/your-friends</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/24/your-friends</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Pet is Healthier Than You</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We deserve some respect. You deserve some respect. You are important to other people, as much as to yourself. You are, therefore, morally obliged to take care of yourself.” (62)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Rule of Life from Dr. Peterson is titled “Treat yourself like someone you are responsible for helping.” Now, to be honest, this chapter took a bit to get in to. It seems like there is a big digression from the original point, but Dr. Peterson ties it all back together in a nice bow to help get the full impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-pet-is-healthier-than-you&quot;&gt;Your Pet is Healthier Than You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think back to the last time you were given a prescription - whether it was for medicine to take daily, a diet to switch to, or healthy habits to start. Looking back to this time, how did you do? Did you stick to it? Did you come out the other side having completed all that was asked? It would not be surprising if you said no. Many people fail to keep up a habit or task they are assigned to them in situations like that. Taking medicine every day for an ear infection for 2 weeks? Well after 1 week I feel fine, so I’m going to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now think about a time when you were responsible for someone/something that then had a similar task. Say your dog needed to take medicine for 2 weeks - how did that go? You probably made sure at all costs that the dog got his/her medicine every day, didn’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that? Why did you make sure that your pet got their medicine daily but when it came to you, you failed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the question that lingers throughout Rule 2. Dr. Peterson takes us all the way back to Genesis, Adam and Eve, and God to tell us why that is and what caused us to act this way. He sums it up nicely by saying that people “shoulder intolerable burdens of self-disgust, self-contempt, shame and self conscious” and that “they are excruciatingly aware of their won faults and inadequacies, real and exaggerated, and ashamed and doubtful of their own value. They [people] believe that other people shouldn’t suffer, and they will work diligently and altruistically to help them alleviate it” (59).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-plan-for-self-authoring&quot;&gt;A Plan for Self Authoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson’s for this fault is fairly simple - “to treat yourself as if you were someone you are responsible for help is… to consider what would be truly good for you” (62). Yes, I know that is a loaded statement - how do you know what is truly good for you? Dr. Peterson says it does not  “what would make you happy” or “what you want” (62), but that you need to look to the future, thinking about it, and ask yourself questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What might my life look like if I were caring for myself properly?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What career would challenge me and render me productive and helpful?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What should I be doing when I have some freedom, to improve my health, expand my knowledge, and strengthen my body?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those questions do not have easy answers - it will take time, introspection, and reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson knows all this, so (surprisingly not mentioned in the book), he has a product for that called &lt;a href=&quot;https://selfauthoring.com/&quot;&gt;Self Authoring&lt;/a&gt;. Self Authoring is an online tool where you go through steps of answering these questions and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People who spend time writing carefully about themselves become happier, less anxious and depressed and physically healthier. They become more productive, persistent and engaged in life. This is because thinking about where you came from, who you are and where you are going helps you chart a simpler and more rewarding path through life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in answering these questions and learning more about yourself and what “would be truly good for you”, I would recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://selfauthoring.com/&quot;&gt;Self Authoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/23/treat-yourself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/23/treat-yourself</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>At the Very Least, Stand Up Straight and Don't Be a Lobster</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To stand up straight with your shoulders back is to accept the terrible responsibility of life, with eyes wide open. It means deciding to voluntarily transform the chaos of potential into the realities of habitable order.” (27)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson’s first Rule of Life is simple - &lt;strong&gt;Stand Up Straight With Your Shoulders Back&lt;/strong&gt;. This phrase is something we may have all heard growing up as a kid. Our parents tell us to keep our back straight at the dinner table or to stop slouching while walking the aisles of a grocery store. In my mind back that, I thought that had to deal with posture only. It still does have an impact on your posture - you obviously don’t want a slouched back the rest of your life - but it also helps reinforce key points from Dr. Peterson’s first rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-lobsters-tell-a-good-story&quot;&gt;How Lobsters Tell a Good Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lobsters have been around for years. Okay well years is an understatement - millennia is a better descriptor. Lobsters have been around since dinosaurs roamed the earth, and, helpful to scientists, have fairly simple nervous systems. This makes lobsters (I know, oddly enough) ripe for scientific studies. In studying lobsters, scientists have found a very clear dominance hierarchy. Dominance hierarchies exists in many aspects of our life, but in lobsters we can clearly see how it pans out within animals. Lobsters engage in a battle for areas on the sea floor for them to live and in doing so, establish a pecking order based off of the winner and losers. This is where &lt;a href=&quot;blog/2018/04/19/price-s-law&quot; title=&quot;Price's Law&quot;&gt;Price’s Law&lt;/a&gt; comes into place - the more a lobster wins, the higher likelihood he will keep on winning while if a lobster loses, the chances that he will keep on losing is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may see where this is going already, but what Dr. Peterson is getting at in this chapter is that this same idea applies to humans. Lobsters have been around for quite a long time and have this hierarchy engrained in their central nervous system. Humans also have this dominance hierarchy within our society and within our central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-negative-loops&quot;&gt;Creating Negative Loops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with lobsters, humans also fall in the tendency of creating loops within our brain that “predict” ahead of time what our outcomes will be. These loops are what can be the downfall, or rise, of our “status” in the dominance hierarchy. You know those days where everything seems to go wrong? One thing goes wrong, and then another, and then you start telling yourself throughout the day “everything is going wrong” or “I can’t do this” or “of course this is happening to me.” That is you creating a negative feedback loop within your brain that then is predicting negative events to happen. People with depression experience this first hand - they feel like they are a burden or are useless, so they draw back from being with friends and family, but in drawing back, they are reinforcing the idea that no body wants to be with them, so they draw back more. From there you can see how depression can be a deep spiral into seclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-positive-loops&quot;&gt;Creating Positive Loops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson’s first rule is then simple - &lt;strong&gt;Stand Up Straight  With Your Shoulders Back&lt;/strong&gt;. Standing up means you are facing life as it is - you are accepting the responsibilities and burden of life. When you do that, your central nervous system and brain can then respond differently to events. Instead of getting hit with a problem and accepting defeat, you see it as a challenge. When you face a challenge instead of backing down, you then start creating positive loops that reinforce what you are doing. Instead of slouching over, head down, looking small which indicates defeat and a low “status”, you are “deciding to voluntarily transform the chaos of potential into the realities of habitable order” (27). Standing up straight releases serotonin into your neural pathways which help face the challenges and the obstacles, and then helps you overcome them. The positive loop continues on. People start noticing you and assume that you are “competent and able”, adding onto the positive feedback look. From there, “you will find it easier to pay attention to subtle social clues,” “your conversations will flow better,” and “you’ll be more likely to meet with people” (28). Dr. Peterson even states that standing up straight will “genuinely increase the probably that good things will happen to you” (28).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you continue your day going forward, start making mental notes of when you feel slouched over, head down. Recognize what may have led to that scenario, grab it by the horns, and stand up straight. Go for a walk around your office standing straight with your shoulders back. That step forward will help push you towards the right positive feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/19/at-the-very-least-stand-up-straight</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/19/at-the-very-least-stand-up-straight</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Price's Law</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To those who have everything, more will be given; from those who have nothing, everything will be taken. -Matthew 25:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have heard of this &lt;strong&gt;Price’s Law&lt;/strong&gt; before without realizing there was a name to it. Price’s Law states that the top 1% percent do as much/have as much as the bottom 50%. Take wealth for example - the top 1% has as much money as the bottom 50%. “The richest eighty-five people have as much as the bottom three and a half billion” (8). This law is not only related to money though. In many aspects of our lives this law can be applied - in the work place environment we have top performers that do more work than a group of bottom performers; in music, “a small fraction of the music composed by a small fraction of all the classical composers who have ever composed make up almost all the classical music that the world knows and loves” (8). We all know Bach, Beethoven, Mozart, and (maybe you know) Tchaikovsky. Those 4 musician’s music make up most of the classical music performed by orchestras. Not only just their music, but of their pieces, only a fraction of those get performed by orchestras - a fraction within a fraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea permeates multiple areas of our life - below is a chart from Reddit, a popular online website. It even shows that a small number of users have the most karma (fake internet points) over the vast majority. It makes you wonder - where else is this occurring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/04/19/ZJwEgaH.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/JordanPeterson/comments/6dhbbg/prices_law_and_pareto_distributions_everywhere/?st=jg6iebzx&amp;amp;sh=50a5f792&quot; title=&quot;Source&quot;&gt;(Source)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/18/price-s-law</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/18/price-s-law</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deskbound - Google Talk [Video]</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t want to buy the book? I would still recommend it, but if not, check out this talk from Kelly Starrett brought to you by “Talks at Google.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kfg_e6YG37U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/12/deskbound-video</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/12/deskbound-video</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Or Are You a Rebel?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-four-tendencies-by-gretchen-rubin&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt; by Gretchen Rubin&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For Rebels, the ability to choose is so important that sometimes they make a choice–even when it’s against their own self-interest or it’s not what they prefer–just to reassure themselves that they &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make that choice. (156)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last of the Four Tendencies under &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt;, ask yourself if you think these statements apply to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You think I can’t business? Watch me.” (157)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You do better when there are no expectations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resist anything “perceived to be an attempt at control” (160)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer pressure may have the opposite result on you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resist labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebels are the smallest Tendency out of all of the Four Tendencies. Rebels &lt;em&gt;resist both outer and inner expectations.&lt;/em&gt; When asking a Rebel to do something, the Rebel is very likely to resist whatever the ask or expectation is. When pushed further on it, the chances the Rebel does it goes down even more. Rebels want to do everything in their own time, and, if someone comes in and pushes them or puts an expectation on them, that may ruin the progress the Rebel has made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;since-rebels-resist-both-outer-and-inner-expectations-the-best-thing-you-can-do-when-workingliving-with-a-rebel-is-frame-the-expectation-as-a-choice-for-the-rebel-to-make-provide-all-the-facts-and-information-but-any-pressure-applied-that-sets-an-expectation-will-not-work-rebels-need-to-feel-like-it-is-something-they-are-in-control-of-and-that-they-decided-rebels-also-respond-well-to-challenges---if-a-rebel-wants-to-lose-weight-it-may-be-better-to-say-looks-like-you-arent-going-to-the-gym-today-instead-of-asking-are-you-headed-to-the-gym-the-second-statement-would-most-likely-get-a-no-and-rebellion-of-not-going-to-the-gym-because-someone-else-is-expecting-them-to-go-to-the-gym&quot;&gt;Since Rebels resist both outer and inner expectations, the best thing you can do when working/living with a Rebel is frame the expectation as a choice for the Rebel to make. Provide all the facts and information but any pressure applied that sets an expectation will not work. Rebels need to feel like it is something they are in control of and that they decided. Rebels also respond well to challenges - if a Rebel wants to lose weight, it may be better to say “looks like you aren’t going to the gym today” instead of asking “are you headed to the gym?” The second statement would most likely get a “no” and rebellion of not going to the gym because someone else is expecting them to go to the gym.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Famous Questioners: Chris Guillebeau (Author of &lt;em&gt;The $100 Startup&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/10/the-rebel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/10/the-rebel</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maybe You're an Obliger?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-four-tendencies-by-gretchen-rubin&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt; by Gretchen Rubin&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Obliger is the rock of the world. At work, at home, and in life, not only are Obligers the bigger groups, they’re the ones whom people count on the most.” (103)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s topic under &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt;, ask yourself if you think these statements apply to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I put my patients/clients/research team/family ahead of myself.” (103)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You make time for others but struggle with making time for yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No problem meeting expectations set by others&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May struggle to say no to requests even if you have a heavy workload already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obligers are the most populous Tendency out of all of them, so it may not be surprising if you fall into the category (statistically speaking). Obligers are those that &lt;em&gt;meet outer expectations&lt;/em&gt; but &lt;em&gt;struggle with meeting inner expectations.&lt;/em&gt; If you know someone that succeeds at work when they have tasks to do set out in front of them by their boss but that person can’t seem to hit the gym even though they want to, they are probably an Obliger. Obligers can sometimes struggle with saying “no” to others while also being okay with letting their personal commitments slide in place of other’s asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obligers benefit most from external accountability. Whether that is a coach, an instructor, a friend, a spouse, or an app, external accountability helps Obligers change those inner expectations into outer expectations they can hold themselves accountable for. The external accountability can be as simple as disappointing your family if you don’t make it home for dinner (if you have a lot of work) or being charged a payment if you don’t make a fitness class; external accountability helps Obligers meet their inner goals while also balancing their external expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Famous Questioners: Tiger Woods&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/09/the-obliger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/09/the-obliger</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Or Are You an Questioner?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-four-tendencies-by-gretchen-rubin&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt; by Gretchen Rubin&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Questioners show a deep commitment to information, logic, and efficiency. They want to gather their own facts, decide for themselves, and act with good reason; they object to anything they consider arbitrary, ill-reasoned, ill-informed, or ineffective.” (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s topic under &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt;, ask yourself if you think these statements apply to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“But why?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You dislike the statement “it’s always been done that way”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Value research and learning information about why or what something is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May dislike others questioning your decisions because you’ve already done all the research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look for more efficient and better ways to do tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Question arbitrary rules if they don’t have a reason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again that is just a short rundown of some of the characteristics of Questioners, but I think the name of “Questioner” provides an fairly accurate description itself. Questioners are those who resist outer expectations and meet inner expectations. Rubin shares that Questioners resist the outer expectations until they are given enough information to justify and prove that expectation. When that occurs, those outer expectations often then become inner expectations. If you’ve ever gone to the doctor or the dentist where they told you to “floss every day” or “take this medicine while you eat” and you questioned these statements, chances are you may be a Questioner. The reason for questioning a doctor are part of who you are though - you do not blindly follow rules or authority figures. You want to know the “why” behind the statements, then it will be easier to meet those expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No tendency is perfect though. To others, Questioners may seem like “not a team player” if their bosses have different expectations of them. A Questioner may pepper a team meeting or a boss about why something is which can seem like insubordination or lack of cooperation. Questioners can also get stuck in “analysis-paralysis”. Instead of making a quick decision, there needs to be lots of research, information, and understanding before that decision can be made…which may lead to a “paralysis” of decision making. If you’ve been putting off buying a new car because you’ve been doing research for so long, you may be a Questioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Does that sound like you? Or do you know someone who falls into this category? A good way to help and work with a Questioner is by setting constraints on them. To avoid analysis-paralysis, give the Questioner a deadline or have them max out at a couple options and make them choose from those. For a new car, give them 5 options and a deadline by the end of the month. That way their research is focused but also under a time constraint. Also when dealing with a Questioner, have a “why” for your statements. Giving them “because so-and-so said so” or “because it’s always been done that way” will not satisfy a Questioner. “Why do we need to floss every night?” “Because floss helps prevents ABC which then helps your teeth with XYZ.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Famous Questioners: Jane Eyre&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/06/the-questioner</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/06/the-questioner</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You an Upholder?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-four-tendencies-by-gretchen-rubin&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Four Tendencies&lt;/em&gt; by Gretchen Rubin&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Upholders are those people who readily respond to outer and inner expectations alike. They meet the work deadline, and they keep the New Year’s resolution, without much fuss.” (27)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by now you’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/04/identify-your-tendency&quot;&gt;take Gretchen Rubin’s quiz&lt;/a&gt; to find out which tendency you are, but ask yourself if you think these quotes apply to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You observe the rules even when it’s more sensible to ignore them”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there is a bathroom marked with the opposite sex, you are unable to use it even if it is a single bathroom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You like crossing items off a list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You feel uneasy about changes to routines, habits, or schedules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning is your thing and deviating from it can be tough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After a tough day, you would feel guilty or worse if you skipped a scheduled workout as opposed to letting yourself off the hook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that’s just a quick, quick, quick rundown of some of the characteristics of Upholders, but hopefully you see my point. Upholders can meet the outer expectations and also meet their inner expectations for themselves. Upholders are often reliable though, they follow-through on what the say, and stick to a schedule. Strengths include “self-starter, self-motivated, conscientious, reliable, and thorough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tendencies have a weakness though. You may find Upholders can seem “cold” when plans change or diverge from what is expected. They can be uptight and rigid with what they want - if they want to stick to a schedule, that may seem a bit excessive. Bending of rules makes them anxious or nervous, and, now this is not from the book but my own opinion, but taking risks that may break the rules does not sound appealing. Upholders may also have trouble delegating work because they know they can do it and do not know if others will do as good of a job. They will also get frustrated with others are not on the same wavelength or expectation level as them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Does that sound like you? Or do you know someone who falls into this category? Well if you know that about a person, that can help you in your interactions. If you are frustrated because your coworker or spouse isn’t being “letting loose” and doing something that bends the rules, it may be because they are an Upholder. Or maybe you have an appointment and the Upholder is pressuring you to get ready quickly so you won’t be late - don’t take that as being mean or cold-hearted, that’s just who they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Famous Upholders: Hermoine Granger&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/05/the-upholder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/05/the-upholder</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
