<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Guebert</title>
    <description>Write a description of your website here.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:02:58 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 06:02:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accountability MVP Part 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay so I’ve become a bit wrapped up in the &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot;&gt;Accountability Calendar&lt;/a&gt; - and by wrapped up I mean working on it because it is fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some new features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streaks: See what the longest streak for each month was.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall totals: see how many days out of the month I actually completed the goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shades of green: if I completed more than 1 that day, the shade is a little darker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple Months! (Big one!) You can now view my previous months, back to January when I started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What other features would be cool? My thoughts have been&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some sort of chart to show progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More data per day - if you hover over a day, it shows what activities or when the event was completed. For example, on “Exercise” it shows what exercise I completed, how far, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integration with other services (like Strava) so you dont have to actually input the data. But, that is also a nice feeling of “checking” off a day, maybe not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milestones and goal setting - my goal was set towards Memorial Day, so maybe a countdown?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal profile - create a web app and you could find an individual user like “someurl.com/@kevinguebert” (okay this is a bigger undertaking…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple layouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emails when someone is going “streaking” - highlight someone currently streaking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public/social accountability when someone misses more than 1 day in a row? (or more than X days that are set)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would other people be interested in this?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/16/mvp-updates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/16/mvp-updates</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accountability MVP Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea&quot;&gt;Three days ago&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about a simple, public calendar to update on my goal progress. &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot;&gt;Here is the current version of the calendar&lt;/a&gt;. Now, the progress may not look like much, but I’ve simplified it much much more coding-wise and made it more extensible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what was changed is that instead of manually creating a calendar for each one, it now dynamically creates a calendar based off of a JSON (data) file. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/kevinguebert/a31a2e8a09d7054dccca805ee05cb8f3&quot;&gt;You can actually view the file online&lt;/a&gt; that I am using. So here is the flow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fetch the file from that url&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go down the list of each goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each goal, go to the “status” data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “status” contains all the months that I’ve been tracking. Right now there is only May, but it can be added to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each month, go through all the days. If a day is marked with anything besides “0”, then I completed it that day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the UI elements for those days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add it to the webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppperr simple, but I love it. Why? Well, I actually won’t have to get into the code if I want to update a day. I can just edit the &lt;a href=&quot;(https://gist.github.com/kevinguebert/a31a2e8a09d7054dccca805ee05cb8f3)&quot;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;, hit save, and then it will update the calendar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, multiple months!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/15/accountability-mvp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/15/accountability-mvp</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you really fasting?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-longevity-diet-by-dr-valter-longo&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Longevity Diet&lt;/em&gt; by Dr. Valter Longo&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intermittent fasting, in my humble opinion, is a bit of a buzz word right now. Definitely growing in popularity, people are trying it out and supposedly seeing some of the benefits from it. A couple weeks ago, a friend of mine talked about how he participates in intermittent fasting. I probed him more about it, and he talked about how he usually skips breakfast and fasts until lunch. I asked him a little more about his diet and how it was going, and he added that he does it every once in a while. The day before he had breakfast but that morning, he was fasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversation ended, but that last part kind of stuck with me. It made me question what he was doing - was he really fasting or was he just not eating that morning? What’s the difference? If you have breakfast one day, and then don’t the next day, to me that sounds like you skipped breakfast, but people seem to get away with spinning it as “fasting” now-a-days. Seems like a buzzword-fad to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Longo seems to share this sentiment. He states that the hype around intermittent fasting “allows people to improve and pick and choose periods of fasting…giving the impression that just because they all involve some period of ‘abstention from food’ they are similar or equivalent and all provide health benefits” (101). That however, is not true. There is definitely a difference between “skipping a meal” and “fasting.” Dr. Longo defines that fasting can only be “periods of abstention from food lasting two or  three days or more” (101). Fasting is not skipping breakfast that day or not eating a meal. If you chain those days together, then you start to get the effects and benefits of fasting. But don’t cheat or label what you are doing anything else, the only person you are really hurting is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/14/intermittent-fasting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/14/intermittent-fasting</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Upgraded Morning Routine</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-own-the-day-own-your-life-by-aubrey-marcus&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; by Aubrey Marcus&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/01/12/morning-routine&quot;&gt;Way back in January&lt;/a&gt; I talked about my morning routine and how it works for me. For the past couple months, I’ve stuck with it probably 95% of the time with the 5% missing coming from when visitors are here or when I’m traveling. Recently (like this past week), I’ve shaken things up a little more though. I &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; that I am most productive in the morning, so I asked why not give myself more time then? I decided to shift my sleep clock around and ended up waking up 30 minutes earlier than previously. The effects have been dramatic to say the least. That simple 30 minutes seems like I have extra hours every morning. If you want to get more done before work, I would recommend moving the alarm 15 or 30 minutes earlier, you may get all you need done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night while doing a weekly check-in call with my good friend Joe, we talked about this and how it could be beneficial to add some light exercises in. I have more time, why not? Coincidentally enough, last night I also started reading &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; which also talks about exercise every morning. That seems like a sign, right? Aubrey Marcus’s prescribed morning routine is simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink water (he has a ‘cocktail’ concoction)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get some sunlight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Light exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He water concoction is water, salt, and some a little bit of lemon to replenish the body of being dehydrated all night. Then “blast” yourself with blue-light from the sun (after every sleep cycle, including naps). Finally, light exercise to get the blood flowing. He does 23 burpees, but anything including yoga can help. Why does he prescribe this? To get your day started on the right foot. Don’t roll over in bed, hit snooze, check social media immediately, and let others define how you feel in the morning. Start your day off under your control and get your body moving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/14/a-morning-routine</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/14/a-morning-routine</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Accountability Idea/MVP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/03/04/march-tracking&quot;&gt;A while back&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about how I use IFTTT and Zapier to do some basic accountability tracking. By using a Google Calendar and the two mentioned services, every time I completed a task that I set up as one I wanted to track, it would post to my calendar. Thinking more about it today, it could be fairly simple to get a service together to have a user highlight 2-3 top priority habits and create a visual system to keep them accountable. On my wall right now, I have 3 calendars set up so I can cross off the tasks I complete every day. The idea is to transfer that to a publicily accountable place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brainstorm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reminder every day at user determined time to have them review their tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A simple Google Form for them to check “yes” or “no” if completed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Form updates a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IFTTT/Zapier checks if a new row has been added to the spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a habit was completed that day, update a calendar online by crossing off that day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—- UPDATE 5:05PM —-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the idea. Even though I posted this less than an hour ago since this update, I did some work. &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out my accountability progress in May&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you think of the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Make Useless Things [Video]</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A reminder that not everything has to be perfect, sometimes asking the right questions is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c0bsKc4tiuY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/11/create-useless-things</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/11/create-useless-things</guid>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create Meaningful Relationships</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Relationships don’t deepen naturally. In the absence of action, they will stall.” (246)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about some of the relationships you have right now. Whether it is coworkers, friends, family, or acquaintances, how would you rate those relationships? Some of them may be extremely deep and meaningful while others may just be surface level. What makes the meaningful relationships &lt;em&gt;meaningful&lt;/em&gt;? How do we get more of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think more about those meaningful relationships, can you think of times that helped strengthen them? Maybe it was a fireside talk or a chat over coffee. What happened in those instances? You probably notice that you and your partner were both responsive to each other. One person would share something below surface level, then the other would respond going a bit deeper. You share vulnerabilities with each other that help strengthen the bond between the two of you. You are taking turns sharing some of you personally with another person, and, as long as the other person does the same, a deeper, more meaningful bond can grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Art Aron, a psychologist, developed a study with 36 questions that students participated in. The 36 questions progressed into more intense and deeper questions as they progressed, and, after the session was over, the two students that shared the questions with each other felt “as close to that stranger as 30% of college students feel to the most intimate relationship in their lives” (245).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sampling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What would constitute a ‘perfect’ day for you?”
“What is the greatest accomplishment of your life?”
“What roles do love and affection play in your life?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now those are just 3 questions out of 36, but check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/open-gently/201310/36-questions-bring-you-closer-together&quot;&gt;36 Questions to Bring You Closer Together&lt;/a&gt; to view all of them and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0146167297234003&quot;&gt;Art Aron’s study&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. Then, challenge yourself today to take one relationship and push &lt;em&gt;a little&lt;/em&gt; deeper than usual and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How have you failed today?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What did you guys fail at this week?” (130)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a powerful question. What have you failed at this week? The founder of Spanxx, Sara Blakely, was asked this question at the dinner table every night from her father. What have you done this week that lead to failure…and then what did you learn from it? This question has two solid reasons behind why you should ask yourself it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It normalizes failures. If you ask yourself this question every day, failing doesn’t seem like that big of a deal. It “loses some of its menace.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It requires you to stretch. When you are pushed to fail every day or every week, it requires you to get outside your comfort zone, outside your box, and push yourself to do something you hadn’t before. If you fail, you learn. And when you’ve been failing every day, it doesn’t seem like that big of a deal when you fail again - you know how to get yourself back up and push forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Cater to Your Negative Users</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Research has shown, again and again, that we tend to obsess about problems and negative information…Negative feedback packs a heavier punch than positive; we obsess about 1 negative comment in a collection of 10 supportive ones.” (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a second that you have a business with hundreds of thousands of users. Some users are loyal and love your product, some are indifferent, and some dislike your product. Now you are incharge of making your users happier - what would your plan of action be? You don’t need to worry about the loyal users, they are already happy and love the product. You have to decide if you want to spend time on getting the people that “dislike” your product to be “indifferent” or spend the time on getting the people who are “indifferent” to be “loyal.” Which would you choose? Most of us would think spend time on the people who have had the most negative time - make them a bit happier, cater to their needs, and make their experience better, right? That seems to make the most sense. The data however, speaks differently. The unhappy, “dislike” group of users spends the &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; amount of money on your product while the “loyal” group spends the &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; amount of money. In that case, it would make more sense to get more users in the “loyal” category instead of just being “indifferent.” Indifferent users spend more than the “dislike” group but not as much as the “loyal” group. If you can then improve the experience of the “indifferent” group to be more like the “loyal” group, then reseaerch has show you will “earn &lt;em&gt;about 9 times more revenue&lt;/em&gt;” (59). 9 times! Don’t fall into the pit of trying to make the people who don’t care a priority. Instead, try and give the people who &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; care a little more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Rules for Life - A Must Read</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to recommend you a book to read right now, I would recommend you 2 books. The first one is &lt;em&gt;Extreme Ownership&lt;/em&gt; by Jocko Willink. The second one is &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson. These two books are battling it out for the top spot on my list of favorite books of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life&lt;/em&gt; is dense, it’s philosophical, it’s a tough read, but it drives the lesson home hard and impactfully. Are some chapters or pages or stories hard to understand sometimes? Yes. But if you take the time, rewind a bit in, go back a page or two, and start over, the meaning will come to life. I mentioned a couple rules here on this blog, the last one being &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house&quot;&gt;Rule 6&lt;/a&gt;, but I would recommend taking the time to go through all 12 Rules. In theory you could read the title of the chapter and get the quick understanding, but Dr. Peterson goes through and provides the backstory, the build up, and the reasoning for all his rules. If you are looking for a book to read, I would highly recommend it. This book is one that you will want to read once a year as a reminder to yourself of how to act and how to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Dr. Peterson on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jordanbpeterson.com/&quot;&gt;his personal website&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jordanbpeterson&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/jordanpetersonvideos&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
