<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Guebert</title>
    <description>Write a description of your website here.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 17:05:40 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 17:05:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Accountability Idea/MVP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/03/04/march-tracking&quot;&gt;A while back&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about how I use IFTTT and Zapier to do some basic accountability tracking. By using a Google Calendar and the two mentioned services, every time I completed a task that I set up as one I wanted to track, it would post to my calendar. Thinking more about it today, it could be fairly simple to get a service together to have a user highlight 2-3 top priority habits and create a visual system to keep them accountable. On my wall right now, I have 3 calendars set up so I can cross off the tasks I complete every day. The idea is to transfer that to a publicily accountable place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brainstorm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reminder every day at user determined time to have them review their tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A simple Google Form for them to check “yes” or “no” if completed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Form updates a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IFTTT/Zapier checks if a new row has been added to the spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a habit was completed that day, update a calendar online by crossing off that day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—- UPDATE 5:05PM —-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the idea. Even though I posted this less than an hour ago since this update, I did some work. &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check out my accountability progress in May&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you think of the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Make Useless Things [Video]</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A reminder that not everything has to be perfect, sometimes asking the right questions is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c0bsKc4tiuY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/11/create-useless-things</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/11/create-useless-things</guid>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create Meaningful Relationships</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Relationships don’t deepen naturally. In the absence of action, they will stall.” (246)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about some of the relationships you have right now. Whether it is coworkers, friends, family, or acquaintances, how would you rate those relationships? Some of them may be extremely deep and meaningful while others may just be surface level. What makes the meaningful relationships &lt;em&gt;meaningful&lt;/em&gt;? How do we get more of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think more about those meaningful relationships, can you think of times that helped strengthen them? Maybe it was a fireside talk or a chat over coffee. What happened in those instances? You probably notice that you and your partner were both responsive to each other. One person would share something below surface level, then the other would respond going a bit deeper. You share vulnerabilities with each other that help strengthen the bond between the two of you. You are taking turns sharing some of you personally with another person, and, as long as the other person does the same, a deeper, more meaningful bond can grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Art Aron, a psychologist, developed a study with 36 questions that students participated in. The 36 questions progressed into more intense and deeper questions as they progressed, and, after the session was over, the two students that shared the questions with each other felt “as close to that stranger as 30% of college students feel to the most intimate relationship in their lives” (245).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sampling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What would constitute a ‘perfect’ day for you?”
“What is the greatest accomplishment of your life?”
“What roles do love and affection play in your life?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now those are just 3 questions out of 36, but check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/open-gently/201310/36-questions-bring-you-closer-together&quot;&gt;36 Questions to Bring You Closer Together&lt;/a&gt; to view all of them and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0146167297234003&quot;&gt;Art Aron’s study&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. Then, challenge yourself today to take one relationship and push &lt;em&gt;a little&lt;/em&gt; deeper than usual and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How have you failed today?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What did you guys fail at this week?” (130)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a powerful question. What have you failed at this week? The founder of Spanxx, Sara Blakely, was asked this question at the dinner table every night from her father. What have you done this week that lead to failure…and then what did you learn from it? This question has two solid reasons behind why you should ask yourself it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It normalizes failures. If you ask yourself this question every day, failing doesn’t seem like that big of a deal. It “loses some of its menace.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It requires you to stretch. When you are pushed to fail every day or every week, it requires you to get outside your comfort zone, outside your box, and push yourself to do something you hadn’t before. If you fail, you learn. And when you’ve been failing every day, it doesn’t seem like that big of a deal when you fail again - you know how to get yourself back up and push forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Cater to Your Negative Users</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Research has shown, again and again, that we tend to obsess about problems and negative information…Negative feedback packs a heavier punch than positive; we obsess about 1 negative comment in a collection of 10 supportive ones.” (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a second that you have a business with hundreds of thousands of users. Some users are loyal and love your product, some are indifferent, and some dislike your product. Now you are incharge of making your users happier - what would your plan of action be? You don’t need to worry about the loyal users, they are already happy and love the product. You have to decide if you want to spend time on getting the people that “dislike” your product to be “indifferent” or spend the time on getting the people who are “indifferent” to be “loyal.” Which would you choose? Most of us would think spend time on the people who have had the most negative time - make them a bit happier, cater to their needs, and make their experience better, right? That seems to make the most sense. The data however, speaks differently. The unhappy, “dislike” group of users spends the &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; amount of money on your product while the “loyal” group spends the &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; amount of money. In that case, it would make more sense to get more users in the “loyal” category instead of just being “indifferent.” Indifferent users spend more than the “dislike” group but not as much as the “loyal” group. If you can then improve the experience of the “indifferent” group to be more like the “loyal” group, then reseaerch has show you will “earn &lt;em&gt;about 9 times more revenue&lt;/em&gt;” (59). 9 times! Don’t fall into the pit of trying to make the people who don’t care a priority. Instead, try and give the people who &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; care a little more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Rules for Life - A Must Read</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to recommend you a book to read right now, I would recommend you 2 books. The first one is &lt;em&gt;Extreme Ownership&lt;/em&gt; by Jocko Willink. The second one is &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson. These two books are battling it out for the top spot on my list of favorite books of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life&lt;/em&gt; is dense, it’s philosophical, it’s a tough read, but it drives the lesson home hard and impactfully. Are some chapters or pages or stories hard to understand sometimes? Yes. But if you take the time, rewind a bit in, go back a page or two, and start over, the meaning will come to life. I mentioned a couple rules here on this blog, the last one being &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house&quot;&gt;Rule 6&lt;/a&gt;, but I would recommend taking the time to go through all 12 Rules. In theory you could read the title of the chapter and get the quick understanding, but Dr. Peterson goes through and provides the backstory, the build up, and the reasoning for all his rules. If you are looking for a book to read, I would highly recommend it. This book is one that you will want to read once a year as a reminder to yourself of how to act and how to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Dr. Peterson on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jordanbpeterson.com/&quot;&gt;his personal website&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jordanbpeterson&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/jordanpetersonvideos&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create, Not Consume</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Close out of Reddit. Close out of Facebook. Close out of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 minutes later, back on Reddit, back on Facebook, back on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever have one of those days? The days where you are consuming information, refreshing the same websites hoping for something new? The days where you scroll through your Instagram feed, close out of the app, only to open it 5 minutes later to see what’s new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the Consuming Days. Days where all you are doing in taking in information, taking in photos, statuses, news links, and tweets. You know those studies where they look at people using social media and determine their mental health? Consuming Days are the days where one’s mental health declines. Consuming Days are the highlight of those studies. Consuming Days are days where you take in the outside world and apply it to yourself. Consuming Days are the days where you start comparing - comparing yourself to the highlight reel of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want Creating Days. On Creating Days, you’re giving back. Creating Days you’re helping others, interacting with friends and family, building new tools, progressing on your work, and making a difference in the world. Creating Days give you that internal boost of “feeling good.” You’ve done something productive, healthy, and beneficial with your day. You’re Creating, not Consuming. Aim for Creative Days. Code a little. Help others online. Sketch the idea. Raise your hand. Contribute in a meeting. Build that momentum. Create a little, then Create more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/02/create-not-consume</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/02/create-not-consume</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End of April Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;April is over, May is here. Time to check in on those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Goal: By Memorial Day 2018, I want to have 100 new posts on a website about something I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this goal, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/01/31/z-month-1-recap.html&quot;&gt;End of January Reflection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metrics&lt;/strong&gt;: In January, I completed exactly 20 blog posts. To meet my goal of 100 new posts by Memorial Day, I would have to average 20 posts a month(ish). In February, I completed 13 blog posts which put me 7 behind the pace. In March, after having a bit of a lapse in the middle of the month and also including this post, I had 32 blog posts. 
&lt;strong&gt;**
Now for April, I completed only **15 blog posts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding the Data&lt;/strong&gt;: A little bit of a bummer for April. To be honest, I don’t quite have a reason for this low number of 15. Fortunately in March, I had 5 extra to give…but I didn’t expect to need them all in April. My total is now 80, so I have 20 blog posts to write by Memorial Day (which is the average for each month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going Forward&lt;/strong&gt;: May will have to be as strong as March was for me. Reading &lt;strong&gt;12 Rules of Life&lt;/strong&gt; is intense, in depth, and philosophical, but that is not an excuse to not write about it or anything. Memorial Day is 28 days away, so my goal is definitely still attainable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I have come to realize over the past week or so is that 5 months for a SMART goal for me is too long. I’m itching to start something new, get a refresh (or a week off), and set a new date and new goals. I already have some in mind that I’m getting excited about. A new blog CMS, new format, new types of posts, new content…all that good stuff. I also received some great feedback about my writing - &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods&quot;&gt;Walk Out of the Woods&lt;/a&gt; was given some praise for its rawness and original thought. Oftentimes I’m summarizing what I read that morning, but sprinkling in personal thoughts is something I can work on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/01/april-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/01/april-review</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stop Wasting Time and Start Today</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Start to stop doing what you know to be wrong.&lt;/em&gt; Start stopping today. Don’t waste time questioning how you know that what you’re doing is wrong, if you are certain that it is.” (158)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 6: Set your house in perfect order before you criticize the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in January of this year, I read Jocko Willink’s &lt;em&gt;Extreme Ownership&lt;/em&gt; book which talks about taking ownership of everything that happens in your life. Whether it is good or bad, Jocko states that by taking ownership of it, you can learn and move forward. Rule 6 in Dr. Peterson’s book reminds me of that same mentality. If you are suffering, he asks you to start small and consider your circumstances. Reflect a little. “Have you taken full advantage of the opportunities offered to you? Are you working hard on your career, or even your job, or are you letting bitterness and resentment hold you back and drag you down?” (157) Peterson asks you to think about what you can be doing better to change the circumstances of your suffering, of your life, before going out and blaming it on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Stop acting in that particular, despicable manner. Stop saying those things that make you weak and ashamed. Say only those things that make you strong. Do only those things that you could speak of with honour.” (158)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Walk Out of the Woods</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-walk-in-the-woods-rediscovering-america-on-the-appalachian-trail-by-bill-bryson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods: Rediscovering America on the Appalachian Trail&lt;/em&gt; by Bill Bryson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A terribly misguided and terribly funny tale of adventure…choke on your coffee funny.” - &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay this may be a bit against the norm here, but, reading that quote above talking about &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;, you would expect a more comedy-like book, right? &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt; for me though was more…depressing…than comedy. Bill Bryson paints a wonderful picture of what life on the trail is like, but he sprinkles his story with the problems and failings of those in charge of the trail and the history. To be brutally honest, I’m not sure I laughed once. Not even close to “choke on your coffee funny.” &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt; falls more on the satire train than comedy (as another review notes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I find it more depressing than funny? What you learn about the Appalachian Trail does not give you hope for the future. Bryson consistently mentions the problems and ailments of it all - species going extinct, plants and forests disappearing, commercialization, and park rangers that “don’t care.” His stories revolve more around what could have been instead of appreciating what is currently there. It all seems more like a story of complaining about what those in the past did instead of offering a solution for the future. Farmers took down a patch of trees that now lays barren? What can you do to see the positive instead of sit and complain? Maybe it’s more of a realist approach, but after reading &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;, I would say I was convinced more to not hike the Appalachian Trail instead of inspired to see its wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
