<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Guebert</title>
    <description>Write a description of your website here.
</description>
    <link>https://kevinguebert.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://kevinguebert.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:28:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:28:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Define Your Goals, Define Your Fears</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past January, I set a goal for myself of writing 100 posts before Memorial Day. Well, here it is: post #100. I’ve learned a few things over the course of the past 5 months that will come in another post, but one thing I have been pondering on is a TedTalk given by Tim Ferriss. Tim Ferriss talks about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5J6jAC6XxAI&quot;&gt;defining your fears&lt;/a&gt; in a process he calls &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2017/05/15/fear-setting/&quot;&gt;fear setting&lt;/a&gt;. With this process, you define and think about some of the worst case scenarios that could happen for some setting. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2017/05/15/fear-setting/&quot;&gt;In his blog post&lt;/a&gt;, he has 7 Q&amp;amp;As to get you going to move past any inaction you may have and help you define your fears. Check it out - if goal setting hasn’t been your thing before, maybe fear setting is more up your alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5J6jAC6XxAI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/27/goal-setting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/27/goal-setting</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discover Your Love Language</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 5 Love Languages&lt;/em&gt; by Gary Chapman has been on my list of “to reads” for the past couple of months. After reading it though, I wish I had spent the day (yes, it is a ‘read in a day’ kind of length) to read it and understand more about it all. The interesting part about &lt;em&gt;The 5 Love Languages&lt;/em&gt; is that it does necessarily have to apply to a romantic relationship. The book is definitely centered around those and marriages, but learning the languages can help you with other relationships. Thus, I would put &lt;em&gt;The 5 Love Languages&lt;/em&gt; on my recommended list - a must read for everyone who is looking to learn more about themselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.5lovelanguages.com/&quot;&gt;You can also learn about your love language online&lt;/a&gt; - if you don’t feel like reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/26/love-languages</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/26/love-languages</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Trackers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following along with this site for a bit, you’ve noticed a couple design changes. I’m not going to lie, there will probably be another one coming soon, but I wanted to highlight one of the pain points I’ve been struggling with in creating this - where to list, keep track of, and showcase books. So far this year, I’ve read more than I expected to and I want to be able to keep track of these books and share my thoughts on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back, I was using an app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://shelftaught.com/&quot;&gt;ShelfTaught&lt;/a&gt;. The application is fairly simple, you add books to your “shelf”, rate them, organize them, and move them around however you see fit. A big bonus of that was that I could embed those books into this site without someone having to leave here. Unfortunately though, through unknown reasons, it was slow. You probably saw the blue loading spinner for a bit and I just wasn’t the biggest fan of that while it loads. I don’t mind ShelfTaught, it just isn’t 100% what I’m looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that actually thought, I was using &lt;a href=&quot;http://trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; boards to organize my books. This wasn’t a bad solution as it actually had the ability to other people to add books to my shelf to recommend to me. The interface however, was not up to par. Cluttered would be the best word I would describe it as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most recently, I’ve been looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookclub.cool/&quot;&gt;BookClub&lt;/a&gt; which I discovered on ProductHunt’s Ship page. The biggest pro to this is the design - I’m a big fan. But at the same time, it is early in the stages, so I haven’t been able to fully commit to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds like a lot of complaining, yeah? The last solution is to build something or make something myself, and, unsurprisingly, I kind of like that idea. I built the &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot;&gt;Accountability Calendar&lt;/a&gt; on a whim and fairly quickly, so I’ll see what I can cook up next. I would also like the ability to get all posts for each book I’ve read, and, this would be an “extra” feature if other people could use it, allow people to use their own Amazon affiliate links. So maybe be on the lookout for that? Who knows, there is a lot to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/24/track-books</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/24/track-books</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Forgive Yourself</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-own-the-day-own-your-life-by-aubrey-marcus&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; by Aubrey Marcus&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If we don’t forgive ourselves, all that knowledge from our past failures will instead petrify into useless information, and we will continue to believe deep down that we deserve to get beaten down by life.” (365)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inspiring end to &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; - learn to forgive yourself because all you can do is your best. Recently over the past couple of weeks, I’ve been struggling with this part of “Owning the Day.” Marcus’ points tread similarly to &lt;em&gt;Extreme Owenership&lt;/em&gt; by Jocko Willink. As humans, we often think it’s better to blame others, create excuses or reasons, and hide behind things we make up. If we instead take the Extreme Ownership point of view, we be able to “look our mistakes right in the eye”, learn from them, and move own. From there, as long as we are doing our best, that is all we can ask for. If our best isn’t what we envisioned, then we forgive ourselves knowing that we gave it our all, and learn from what happened. That way, next time, we can use what we’ve learned and do it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Your day is never going to be perfect…But that doesn’t mean I don’t wake up and do my best the next day” (365)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/23/forgive-yourself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/23/forgive-yourself</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Valter Longo &amp; Rich Roll [Video]</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I finished &lt;em&gt;The Longevity Diet&lt;/em&gt; by Dr. Valter Longo. I was introduced to this book and to Dr. Longo by a guest on the Rich Roll podcast, one of my favorite podcasts. With lots of people asking Rich to bring Dr. Longo onto the podcast, he was finally able to make it happen. If you don’t want to or don’t have the time to read the book, at least listen to the podcast, it’ll be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Odpt9afBlYY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/22/rich-longo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/22/rich-longo</guid>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Own Your Day, Own Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-own-the-day-own-your-life-by-aubrey-marcus&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; by Aubrey Marcus&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note - I have not finished &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; yet, these are preliminary thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 125 pages left of Aubrey Marcus’ book &lt;em&gt;Own the Day, Own Your Life&lt;/em&gt; and I’ve come to a thought that may go a bit against what he preaches. Marcus leads you through a journey of how he thinks your day should look - with morning exercise to get the blood flowing, with supplements, food to eat, training, etc. In this journey, he throws out some recommendations, a couple “life hacks”, and small anecdotes about what he believes or what science says works. Some of this information I find valuable: last week I started doing a little 10-15 minute routine before I left for work to get the blood flowing and I felt great. Other things, not so much. So as with many “self-help”, “self-improvement” type books, I would say this - take the information in, understand it, try it out, and &lt;em&gt;see if it works for you.&lt;/em&gt; Other people prescribe up things to do every day, and for some of us, those things just might not work. That’s okay! If it works for one person, doesn’t mean it will have to work for you. But, that also doesn’t mean you can ignore it. Experiment and learn about yourself while you learn. Maybe Marcus’ prescription fits you perfectly, maybe you need to modify it a little for it to work, or maybe you understand what he is saying but follow a different mantra. All those scenarios are perfectly fine as long &lt;em&gt;as you are doing something.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Something is better than nothing&lt;/strong&gt;, so get after it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/21/own-your-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/21/own-your-day</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Run an Empire App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s post is a small break from my regular-like posts. I’m a big fan of running, and I’m a big fan of discipline and tools that help people reach their goals. Over a year ago (maybe even two?), I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runanempire.com/&quot;&gt;Run an Empire&lt;/a&gt; to help combine those two passions of mine. What is Run an Empire? You know those games where you build settlements, collect coins, protect your village, and all that jazz? Well those games don’t require you to do anything besides stay glued to your phone as much as possible. Run an Empire takes a different approach - if you want to advance in the game, you &lt;strong&gt;have to run&lt;/strong&gt;. You collect territories (hexes) but running through them. The more you run, the more coins you collect, the more you are able to build. Run an Empire promotes running to build your “empire” and not sitting around tapping a million times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/panstudio/run-an-empire-the-real-world-territory-control-gam&quot;&gt;Originally launched as a Kickstarter in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, Run an Empire released the first early access version of their app for both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runanempire.com/beta/&quot;&gt;Android and iOS&lt;/a&gt; this past January. Now that my training schedule has been/will be starting to pick up, I’m using Run an Empire as a companion app to tracking my runs. The app is in early access , still being built, and it still has some bugs to work out, but I would still recommend downloading it and trying it out. I haven’t even experienced the whole gameplay as no one around me has the app yet, so it will be fun when empires start battling it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runanempire.com/&quot;&gt;Official Site&lt;/a&gt; // &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runanempire.com/beta/&quot;&gt;Get Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/18/run-an-empire</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/18/run-an-empire</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>fitness</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accountability MVP Part 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay so I’ve become a bit wrapped up in the &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot;&gt;Accountability Calendar&lt;/a&gt; - and by wrapped up I mean working on it because it is fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some new features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streaks: See what the longest streak for each month was.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall totals: see how many days out of the month I actually completed the goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shades of green: if I completed more than 1 that day, the shade is a little darker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple Months! (Big one!) You can now view my previous months, back to January when I started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What other features would be cool? My thoughts have been&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some sort of chart to show progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More data per day - if you hover over a day, it shows what activities or when the event was completed. For example, on “Exercise” it shows what exercise I completed, how far, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integration with other services (like Strava) so you dont have to actually input the data. But, that is also a nice feeling of “checking” off a day, maybe not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milestones and goal setting - my goal was set towards Memorial Day, so maybe a countdown?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal profile - create a web app and you could find an individual user like “someurl.com/@kevinguebert” (okay this is a bigger undertaking…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple layouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emails when someone is going “streaking” - highlight someone currently streaking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public/social accountability when someone misses more than 1 day in a row? (or more than X days that are set)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would other people be interested in this?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/16/mvp-updates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/16/mvp-updates</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accountability MVP Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/05/12/accountability-idea&quot;&gt;Three days ago&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about a simple, public calendar to update on my goal progress. &lt;a href=&quot;/accountability-calendar/&quot;&gt;Here is the current version of the calendar&lt;/a&gt;. Now, the progress may not look like much, but I’ve simplified it much much more coding-wise and made it more extensible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what was changed is that instead of manually creating a calendar for each one, it now dynamically creates a calendar based off of a JSON (data) file. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/kevinguebert/a31a2e8a09d7054dccca805ee05cb8f3&quot;&gt;You can actually view the file online&lt;/a&gt; that I am using. So here is the flow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fetch the file from that url&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go down the list of each goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each goal, go to the “status” data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “status” contains all the months that I’ve been tracking. Right now there is only May, but it can be added to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each month, go through all the days. If a day is marked with anything besides “0”, then I completed it that day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the UI elements for those days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add it to the webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppperr simple, but I love it. Why? Well, I actually won’t have to get into the code if I want to update a day. I can just edit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/kevinguebert/a31a2e8a09d7054dccca805ee05cb8f3&quot;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;, hit save, and then it will update the calendar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, multiple months!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/15/accountability-mvp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/15/accountability-mvp</guid>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you really fasting?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-longevity-diet-by-dr-valter-longo&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Longevity Diet&lt;/em&gt; by Dr. Valter Longo&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intermittent fasting, in my humble opinion, is a bit of a buzz word right now. Definitely growing in popularity, people are trying it out and supposedly seeing some of the benefits from it. A couple weeks ago, a friend of mine talked about how he participates in intermittent fasting. I probed him more about it, and he talked about how he usually skips breakfast and fasts until lunch. I asked him a little more about his diet and how it was going, and he added that he does it every once in a while. The day before he had breakfast but that morning, he was fasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversation ended, but that last part kind of stuck with me. It made me question what he was doing - was he really fasting or was he just not eating that morning? What’s the difference? If you have breakfast one day, and then don’t the next day, to me that sounds like you skipped breakfast, but people seem to get away with spinning it as “fasting” now-a-days. Seems like a buzzword-fad to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Longo seems to share this sentiment. He states that the hype around intermittent fasting “allows people to improve and pick and choose periods of fasting…giving the impression that just because they all involve some period of ‘abstention from food’ they are similar or equivalent and all provide health benefits” (101). That however, is not true. There is definitely a difference between “skipping a meal” and “fasting.” Dr. Longo defines that fasting can only be “periods of abstention from food lasting two or  three days or more” (101). Fasting is not skipping breakfast that day or not eating a meal. If you chain those days together, then you start to get the effects and benefits of fasting. But don’t cheat or label what you are doing anything else, the only person you are really hurting is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/14/intermittent-fasting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinguebert.com/blog/2018/05/14/intermittent-fasting</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
