<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Guebert</title>
    <description>Write a description of your website here.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 20:25:56 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 20:25:56 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create Meaningful Relationships</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Relationships don’t deepen naturally. In the absence of action, they will stall.” (246)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about some of the relationships you have right now. Whether it is coworkers, friends, family, or acquaintances, how would you rate those relationships? Some of them may be extremely deep and meaningful while others may just be surface level. What makes the meaningful relationships &lt;em&gt;meaningful&lt;/em&gt;? How do we get more of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think more about those meaningful relationships, can you think of times that helped strengthen them? Maybe it was a fireside talk or a chat over coffee. What happened in those instances? You probably notice that you and your partner were both responsive to each other. One person would share something below surface level, then the other would respond going a bit deeper. You share vulnerabilities with each other that help strengthen the bond between the two of you. You are taking turns sharing some of you personally with another person, and, as long as the other person does the same, a deeper, more meaningful bond can grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Art Aron, a psychologist, developed a study with 36 questions that students participated in. The 36 questions progressed into more intense and deeper questions as they progressed, and, after the session was over, the two students that shared the questions with each other felt “as close to that stranger as 30% of college students feel to the most intimate relationship in their lives” (245).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sampling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What would constitute a ‘perfect’ day for you?”
“What is the greatest accomplishment of your life?”
“What roles do love and affection play in your life?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now those are just 3 questions out of 36, but check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/open-gently/201310/36-questions-bring-you-closer-together&quot;&gt;36 Questions to Bring You Closer Together&lt;/a&gt; to view all of them and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0146167297234003&quot;&gt;Art Aron’s study&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. Then, challenge yourself today to take one relationship and push &lt;em&gt;a little&lt;/em&gt; deeper than usual and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/10/create-meaningful-relationships</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How have you failed today?</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What did you guys fail at this week?” (130)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a powerful question. What have you failed at this week? The founder of Spanxx, Sara Blakely, was asked this question at the dinner table every night from her father. What have you done this week that lead to failure…and then what did you learn from it? This question has two solid reasons behind why you should ask yourself it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It normalizes failures. If you ask yourself this question every day, failing doesn’t seem like that big of a deal. It “loses some of its menace.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It requires you to stretch. When you are pushed to fail every day or every week, it requires you to get outside your comfort zone, outside your box, and push yourself to do something you hadn’t before. If you fail, you learn. And when you’ve been failing every day, it doesn’t seem like that big of a deal when you fail again - you know how to get yourself back up and push forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/how-have-you-failed</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Cater to Your Negative Users</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-the-power-of-moments-by-chip-heath--dan-heath&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Power of Moments&lt;/em&gt; by Chip Heath &amp;amp; Dan Heath&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Research has shown, again and again, that we tend to obsess about problems and negative information…Negative feedback packs a heavier punch than positive; we obsess about 1 negative comment in a collection of 10 supportive ones.” (60)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a second that you have a business with hundreds of thousands of users. Some users are loyal and love your product, some are indifferent, and some dislike your product. Now you are incharge of making your users happier - what would your plan of action be? You don’t need to worry about the loyal users, they are already happy and love the product. You have to decide if you want to spend time on getting the people that “dislike” your product to be “indifferent” or spend the time on getting the people who are “indifferent” to be “loyal.” Which would you choose? Most of us would think spend time on the people who have had the most negative time - make them a bit happier, cater to their needs, and make their experience better, right? That seems to make the most sense. The data however, speaks differently. The unhappy, “dislike” group of users spends the &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; amount of money on your product while the “loyal” group spends the &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; amount of money. In that case, it would make more sense to get more users in the “loyal” category instead of just being “indifferent.” Indifferent users spend more than the “dislike” group but not as much as the “loyal” group. If you can then improve the experience of the “indifferent” group to be more like the “loyal” group, then reseaerch has show you will “earn &lt;em&gt;about 9 times more revenue&lt;/em&gt;” (59). 9 times! Don’t fall into the pit of trying to make the people who don’t care a priority. Instead, try and give the people who &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; care a little more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/07/bad-is-stronger-than-good</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Rules for Life - A Must Read</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to recommend you a book to read right now, I would recommend you 2 books. The first one is &lt;em&gt;Extreme Ownership&lt;/em&gt; by Jocko Willink. The second one is &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson. These two books are battling it out for the top spot on my list of favorite books of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life&lt;/em&gt; is dense, it’s philosophical, it’s a tough read, but it drives the lesson home hard and impactfully. Are some chapters or pages or stories hard to understand sometimes? Yes. But if you take the time, rewind a bit in, go back a page or two, and start over, the meaning will come to life. I mentioned a couple rules here on this blog, the last one being &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house&quot;&gt;Rule 6&lt;/a&gt;, but I would recommend taking the time to go through all 12 Rules. In theory you could read the title of the chapter and get the quick understanding, but Dr. Peterson goes through and provides the backstory, the build up, and the reasoning for all his rules. If you are looking for a book to read, I would highly recommend it. This book is one that you will want to read once a year as a reminder to yourself of how to act and how to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Dr. Peterson on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jordanbpeterson.com/&quot;&gt;his personal website&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jordanbpeterson&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/jordanpetersonvideos&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/03/rules-of-life-review</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create, Not Consume</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Close out of Reddit. Close out of Facebook. Close out of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 minutes later, back on Reddit, back on Facebook, back on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever have one of those days? The days where you are consuming information, refreshing the same websites hoping for something new? The days where you scroll through your Instagram feed, close out of the app, only to open it 5 minutes later to see what’s new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the Consuming Days. Days where all you are doing in taking in information, taking in photos, statuses, news links, and tweets. You know those studies where they look at people using social media and determine their mental health? Consuming Days are the days where one’s mental health declines. Consuming Days are the highlight of those studies. Consuming Days are days where you take in the outside world and apply it to yourself. Consuming Days are the days where you start comparing - comparing yourself to the highlight reel of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want Creating Days. On Creating Days, you’re giving back. Creating Days you’re helping others, interacting with friends and family, building new tools, progressing on your work, and making a difference in the world. Creating Days give you that internal boost of “feeling good.” You’ve done something productive, healthy, and beneficial with your day. You’re Creating, not Consuming. Aim for Creative Days. Code a little. Help others online. Sketch the idea. Raise your hand. Contribute in a meeting. Build that momentum. Create a little, then Create more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/02/create-not-consume</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/02/create-not-consume</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End of April Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;April is over, May is here. Time to check in on those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Goal: By Memorial Day 2018, I want to have 100 new posts on a website about something I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this goal, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/01/31/z-month-1-recap.html&quot;&gt;End of January Reflection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metrics&lt;/strong&gt;: In January, I completed exactly 20 blog posts. To meet my goal of 100 new posts by Memorial Day, I would have to average 20 posts a month(ish). In February, I completed 13 blog posts which put me 7 behind the pace. In March, after having a bit of a lapse in the middle of the month and also including this post, I had 32 blog posts. 
&lt;strong&gt;**
Now for April, I completed only **15 blog posts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding the Data&lt;/strong&gt;: A little bit of a bummer for April. To be honest, I don’t quite have a reason for this low number of 15. Fortunately in March, I had 5 extra to give…but I didn’t expect to need them all in April. My total is now 80, so I have 20 blog posts to write by Memorial Day (which is the average for each month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going Forward&lt;/strong&gt;: May will have to be as strong as March was for me. Reading &lt;strong&gt;12 Rules of Life&lt;/strong&gt; is intense, in depth, and philosophical, but that is not an excuse to not write about it or anything. Memorial Day is 28 days away, so my goal is definitely still attainable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I have come to realize over the past week or so is that 5 months for a SMART goal for me is too long. I’m itching to start something new, get a refresh (or a week off), and set a new date and new goals. I already have some in mind that I’m getting excited about. A new blog CMS, new format, new types of posts, new content…all that good stuff. I also received some great feedback about my writing - &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods&quot;&gt;Walk Out of the Woods&lt;/a&gt; was given some praise for its rawness and original thought. Oftentimes I’m summarizing what I read that morning, but sprinkling in personal thoughts is something I can work on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/01/april-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/01/april-review</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stop Wasting Time and Start Today</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Start to stop doing what you know to be wrong.&lt;/em&gt; Start stopping today. Don’t waste time questioning how you know that what you’re doing is wrong, if you are certain that it is.” (158)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 6: Set your house in perfect order before you criticize the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in January of this year, I read Jocko Willink’s &lt;em&gt;Extreme Ownership&lt;/em&gt; book which talks about taking ownership of everything that happens in your life. Whether it is good or bad, Jocko states that by taking ownership of it, you can learn and move forward. Rule 6 in Dr. Peterson’s book reminds me of that same mentality. If you are suffering, he asks you to start small and consider your circumstances. Reflect a little. “Have you taken full advantage of the opportunities offered to you? Are you working hard on your career, or even your job, or are you letting bitterness and resentment hold you back and drag you down?” (157) Peterson asks you to think about what you can be doing better to change the circumstances of your suffering, of your life, before going out and blaming it on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Stop acting in that particular, despicable manner. Stop saying those things that make you weak and ashamed. Say only those things that make you strong. Do only those things that you could speak of with honour.” (158)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/set-your-house</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Walk Out of the Woods</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-walk-in-the-woods-rediscovering-america-on-the-appalachian-trail-by-bill-bryson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods: Rediscovering America on the Appalachian Trail&lt;/em&gt; by Bill Bryson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A terribly misguided and terribly funny tale of adventure…choke on your coffee funny.” - &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay this may be a bit against the norm here, but, reading that quote above talking about &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;, you would expect a more comedy-like book, right? &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt; for me though was more…depressing…than comedy. Bill Bryson paints a wonderful picture of what life on the trail is like, but he sprinkles his story with the problems and failings of those in charge of the trail and the history. To be brutally honest, I’m not sure I laughed once. Not even close to “choke on your coffee funny.” &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt; falls more on the satire train than comedy (as another review notes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I find it more depressing than funny? What you learn about the Appalachian Trail does not give you hope for the future. Bryson consistently mentions the problems and ailments of it all - species going extinct, plants and forests disappearing, commercialization, and park rangers that “don’t care.” His stories revolve more around what could have been instead of appreciating what is currently there. It all seems more like a story of complaining about what those in the past did instead of offering a solution for the future. Farmers took down a patch of trees that now lays barren? What can you do to see the positive instead of sit and complain? Maybe it’s more of a realist approach, but after reading &lt;em&gt;Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;, I would say I was convinced more to not hike the Appalachian Trail instead of inspired to see its wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/28/walk-out-of-woods</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Better Than You Were Yesterday</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You are discovering who you are, and what you want, and what you are willing to do. You are finding that the solutions to your particular problems have to be tailored to you, personally and precisely. You are less concerned with the actions of other people, because you have plenty to do yourself.” (110)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3: Compare yourself to who you were yesterday, not to who someone else is today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing to others consumes us. It is one thing that many of us do daily - a job, a car, a physique, money, friends, etc. Comparing ourselves to the versions of others is also detrimental and unfair. How can we take &lt;em&gt;one area&lt;/em&gt; of our life and compare it to the life of someone else? That guy driving the fancy new car seems to have it all, but he could be lonely and wanting a family that you have. The woman running every day may be able to run faster and farther than you, but is struggling financially. Everyone has their own problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Rule 3, Dr. Peterson talks about paying attention - being more aware and opening up our eyes to the possibilities of growth. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJG698U2Mvo&quot;&gt;Watch this video and try it out for yourself&lt;/a&gt;. We all do it - we have a focused view of the possibilities. “I want that higher up position because my life will get better.” That isn’t a bad goal, but a bad reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peterson’s solution is very simple though - &lt;strong&gt;“What could I do, that I would do, to make Life a little better?”&lt;/strong&gt;(109) Think about that. What is one thing you could do today to make life a little better? It could be organizing your bills. It could be going for a walk. It could be messaging the people you’ve been putting off. The beauty of it is that if you ask yourself that question every day and follow through, then in a short amount of time you life will have improved dramatically. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=the+1%25+daily+rule&amp;amp;oq=the+1%25+daily+rule&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i64l3.6532j0j3&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Others have wrote&lt;/a&gt; similar articles about it calling it the 1% rule (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1percentrulebook.com/launch&quot;&gt;someone even has a book about it&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help completing that task? You can tie a reward with it. “If I pay all my bills, I’ll grab a cup of coffee.” Simple, yet effective (as long as you make sure to follow through on the coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What could I do, that I would do, to make Life a little better?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/26/compare-yourself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/26/compare-yourself</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who Are Your Friends</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;post-inspired-by-12-rules-for-life-an-antidote-to-chaos-by-jordan-b-peterson&quot;&gt;Post inspired by &lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan B. Peterson.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you surround yourself with people who support your upward aim, they will not tolerate your cynicism and destructiveness. They will instead encourage you when you do good for yourself and others and punish you carefully when you do not.” (82)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3: Make Friends with People Who Want the Best for You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the first three rules, if I were to recommend a must-read chapter I would recommend Rule 3. Dr. Peterson touches on friends, friendship, and poses the question of why some people chose friends who aren’t good for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you have a friend whose friendship you wouldn’t recommend to your sister, or your father, or your son, why would you have such a friend for yourself?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of recommending a friend is a deep, thought filled question. Personally, it struck a chord. If I wouldn’t recommend this person to hang out with someone else, why am I hanging out with them? You may think loyalty is the answer, right? Dr. Peterson tears that logic apart though - “Friendship is a reciproal arrangement. You are not morally obliged to support someone who is. making the world a worse place.” “You should choose people who want things to be better, not worse” (82).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you are thinking to yourself “but I’m a good person, this person needs my help.” Take a step back and actively look at that relationship. Maybe you are a good person who wants to do the right thing for your friend. But make sure it isn’t an alternative reason. Are you sure you aren’t trying to draw attention to yourself by highlighting your “compassion and good-will”? Or are you sure you’re not trying to help someone to make you feel better about your place and character? Or are you trying to help someone “because it’s easier to look virtuous when standing alongside someone utterly irresponsible”? (79)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may look like you are making progress - long talks with your friend about the possibilities and how you both are doing everything possible. But that isn’t real progress. Instead you may be &lt;em&gt;enabling the delusion&lt;/em&gt; which can end up being worse than you not being there at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does Dr. Peterson recommend? There are tips scattered throughout the chapter of questions to ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Are you so sure th person crying out to be saved has not decided a thousand times to accept his lot of pointless and worsening suffering, &lt;em&gt;simply because it is easier than shouldering any true responsibility&lt;/em&gt;?” (79)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Before you help someone, you should find out why that person is in trouble. You shouldn’t merely assume that he or she is a noble victim of unjust circumstances and explotation…if you buy the story that everything terrible just happened on its own, with no personal responsibility on the part of the victim, you deny that person all agency in the past.” (80)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule 3 makes you think about your life and your friendships. Examine them and ask yourself if you would recommend that person as a friend to others. If you wouldn’t, find out why. Dr. Peterson states “it’s a good thing, not a selfish thing, to choose people who are good for you” (82). Lastly though, Dr. Peterson also states the opposite - it is selfish to use some of these justifications for leaving someone truly in need. Take some time and reflect today on those relationships in your life: maybe you think you may be “saving” someone when in fact you could be doing more harm than good, maybe there are relationships where it is not reciprocal, maybe it is time to reevaluate your position. At the end of the day, look to the rule - “make friends with people who want the best for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/24/your-friends</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/24/your-friends</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>personal-growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
